# Liam Vovk

17039 Duffy's Lane, Palgrave, ON L7E 3C9 | C: 519-278-0016 | liam.vovk@gmail.com

# Summary

Developer with 2 years of experience implementing full stack web and mobile applications. I have hands on experience implementing the microservices architecture as well as writing infrastructure as code to enable rapid application deployment, scalability and availability in the cloud, while following the TDD development process. With a degree in Mathematics and Engineering I also have an intimate knowledge of data structures and algorithms as well as an appreciation for abstract concepts.

#### Technical Skills

- React, React Native, Angular, Node, Rails, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Python, Java, Scala, C, R, MatLab, SQL, NoSQL, Powershell, Bash, Git
- Azure, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, MongoDB, MsSQL

# Experience

#### **Software Developer Intern – RBC Amplify** (May 2017 – August 2017)

- In a team of four we were tasked with the problem, create a banking product to serve the needs of the players in the gig economy. Out of 16 teams our team placed top 5 and presented in front of a panel of RBC executives.
- Implemented an iOS and Android application with React Native, NodeJS, and MongoDB that used several microservices hosted on AWS EC2 instances.
- Developed stateless authentication, real time messaging, and user management microservices.
- Deployed and implemented cloud security on all EC2 instances that comprised the back end of the application.
- Developed the mobile UI that consumed the microservices I deployed in AWS.

## **Software Engineer Intern – Celestica** (May 2016 – May 2017)

- Develop full stack microservices with seamless integration to existing tools.
- Develop custom plugins for dashboarding tool to enable more flexible data visualizations and live querying.
- Develop and test highly available systems in Azure.
- Develop infrastructure as code to enable rapid deployment of applications in the cloud in a highly available and secure manner.
- Mine and perform analysis on data from diverse sources to discover business insights.
- Work on global projects with team members in the Americas and Asia.

## **Student – Queen's University** (September 2013 – Present)

- Designed a PID controller for an unknown system that takes arbitrary input signals and gives fuzzy output signals.
- Developed a fully object oriented fireworks simulation (in Java) whose data was used in a JavaFX GUI.
- Implemented an obstacle detection algorithm for use on an autonomous sailboat built by Queen's Mostly Autonomous Sailboat Team.

#### Education

### **Queen's University**

Bachelor of Applied Science, Mathematics and Engineering (Expected graduation: April 2018)

- Specializing in Computing and Communication with Professional Internship.
- Cumulative GPA 3.86.
- Dean's Scholar and Dean's Honour List.
- Queen's University Excellence Scholarship.